Felipe Daniel Ferreira de Almeida

E-mail address: felipedaniel1910@hotmail.com

Phone number: +55 15 996302580

Linkedin URL: https://www.linkedin.com/in/felipedaniel1910/

City: Itatiba (SP)

PROFILE

Graduated in Control and Automation Engineering from the Federal Technological University of Paraná (UTFPR) and a technical course in Electrical Engineering, with an emphasis on automation and industrial control. Two years of experience in managing people and projects within the academic environment, participating in an extension project in robotics. Professional journey started as an apprentice in Industrial Production at Klingele Paper & Packaging in Nova Campina, SP, followed by an R&D internship at Procter & Gamble, focusing on engineering, analysis and data science. After the internship, hired as Technology Project Manager at P&G, working on automation and IT/OT projects. Advanced proficiency in Python, with experience in ETL, application development and process automation, as well as a strong command of SQL, Power BI and machine learning algorithms. Effective communication, excellent teamwork and fluency in English

EDUCATION

2017 - 2023 - FEDERAL TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY OF PARANA - UTFPR-CP - concluded.

Control and Automation Engineering.

2021 – 2021 – PAULA SOUZA STATE CENTER FOR TECHNOLOGICAL EDUCATION – concluded.

• Middle Level Technical Specialist in Project Management.

2015 - 2016 - ETEC DR DEMÉTRIO DE AZEVEDO JÚNIOR - concluded.

Electrical technical course.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

PROCTER & GAMBLE (P&G)

Position: **Technology Project Manager** – May 2023 – Oct 2023.

- Spearheaded the integration of a novel modular process skid into the Fabric Care OT systems, encompassing the establishment of communication between an Allen Bradley PLC and a Siemens PLC through the utilization of an OPC (Open Protocol Communication) application;
- Undertook a leadership position in coordinating the integration and commencement of automation
 for two recently introduced raw material tanks. This undertaking included the meticulous control of
 valves and pumps through a supervisory system, alongside conducting thorough studies and
 meticulous planning to ensure the safety and reliability of the entire process.
- Assumed a dual role as both a technical leader and project manager leading projects aimed at
 expanding the capacity of the OT network servers. Additionally, I managed a project that aimed to
 extract data regarding the consumption of water, air, gas, electricity, and steam. This data extraction
 will allow comprehensive descriptive, comparative, and predictive analyses with the general
 objective of improving the energy efficiency of production.

Position: Data Scientist/Engineer Intern – Feb 2022 – Apr 2023.

- Developed Python desktop applications (using Tkinter), connecting different data sources (SQL Server, Databricks, etc.), processing and transforming data into information (using SQL and Python libraries such as Pandas), and presenting the results to the end user through a friendly graphical interface;
- Improved the ETL process in the department's tools, migrating from Knime to Python. This allowed performance gain and reliable automation, avoiding manual actions to keep the tools updated.
- Revamped Excel tools using VBA, improving the user experience, automating processes and creating a password-protected area for administrator users, protecting the tools from unwanted changes and ensuring the possibility of maintenance through authorized people.
- Led the data processing automation, connecting dashboards in SQL Server databases and Azure Databricks, allowing automatic updating of data. This facilitated access to current business information in a secure and reliable way, saving the team time during consultations. Managed an NSS project for NWOC changes on Taped products, creating a learning plan, leading the EOs, analyzing the results statistically, and providing a final recommendation to leadership.

KLINGELE PAPER & PACKAGING

Position: Industrial Production Apprentice (Paper Machine Sector) – May 2021 – Jan 2022.

- Implemented data mining and creation of automatic reporting on paper production with Python, saving time for the team.
- Automated Excel spreadsheets using VBA and Python.
- Created a guide to all apprentice roles in the paper machine department, saving time in training new hires.

SKILLS

- Languages: English (fluent); Spanish (intermediate).
- Systems/Tools: Office Package (advanced); Power BI (advanced); SQL Server MS (Advanced); VS Code (advanced); GitHub (advanced); Jupyter Notebook (advanced); Azure Databricks (intermediate); PySpark (intermediate); SAP (intermediate).
- Programming languages: Python (advanced); SQL (advanced); C (advanced); R (intermediate);
 JavaScript (intermediate).